evonik.com 2019-07-04

# Privacy Policy

### Protection of data privacy: Your right—our obligation

You can count on us to protect the privacy of your personal data because protecting your privacy when we process your data is a matter of importance to Evonik Industries AG that is taken into consideration in all of our business processes. 

We’d therefore like to take this opportunity to explain to you the guidelines that we apply to the processing of personal data. The present declaration and any further information that may be pertinent to the processing and use of your personal data will be provided at any location on this site where we ask you to supply such data.

### Scope of processing personal data 

As a general rule, we only collect and utilize your personal data to the extent that is necessary for providing a functional website and our content and services. The collection and utilization of personal data generally only occurs with the user’s consent. Exceptions apply in cases where obtaining consent is impossible for factual reasons and where data processing is permitted by law. 

### Legal basis for processing personal data 

To the extent we obtain the consent of the data subject for processing personal data, Art. 6 (1) (a), EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) serves as the legal basis for processing personal data. 

With regard to processing personal data that is required for the performance of a contract to which the data subject is party, Art. 6 (1) (b), GDPR serves as the legal basis. This also applies to processing steps that are necessary for carrying out pre-contractual measures. 

To the extent processing personal data is required for compliance with legal obligations to which our company is subject, Art 6 (1) (c), GDPR serves as the legal basis. 

In the event that the vital interests of the data subject or of another natural person require processing personal data, Art 6 (1) (d) GDPR serves as the legal basis.

If processing is required for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by our company or by a third party and the interests, fundamental rights and freedoms of the data subject do not override such interests, Art. 6 (1) (f), GDPR serves as the legal basis for processing. 

### Data that we collect 

You can use almost the entirety of Evonik Industries AG website without ever having to supply us with personal data. Only a fraction of the information and services located on our website require you to enter personal data in order to use them.   
Whenever you use the Evonik Industries AG website, the Evonik Industries AG Internet server (web server) automatically records and evaluates technical access data. However, this data cannot be attributed to a specific person, which means that the individual user remains anonymous. 

### Compilation of technical access data 

This technical access data includes, for example, the name of your internet service provider, the IP address, information about the internet browser and the operating system that are in use, the domain name of the website that acts as a platform for a visit to our own website, the average duration of a visit to our website, and the pages called from our website. This data is sent to our web server when individual internet pages are called by your internet browser.   
The legal basis for the temporary storage of data is Art. 6(1) (f), GDPR. The temporary storage of data, including the IP address, by the system is necessary to allow for delivery of the website to the user’s computer. For this purpose, the IP address of the user and other data must remain saved for the duration of the session.

### Cookies 

We also add cookies to some areas of our website. Cookies are small data elements that an internet server can send to your computer, thereby allowing it to be identified during your visit to our website and making it easier for you to use our website. Cookies do not cause any damage on your computer and do not contain viruses. We don’t use cookies to gather personal data. You can set your internet browser to tell you whether cookies are being accepted or refused. For more information on cookies, consult the help files in your internet browser. Deactivating cookies may limit this website’s functionality.   
We use this technical access data to continually enhance the appeal, usability and contents of our website, and to detect any technical problems with the site.   
The legal basis for processing personal data together with the use of technically necessary cookies is Art. 6(1)(f), GDPR.

### Personal data 

We collect, process and utilize your personal data only if you provide us with it voluntarily.   
This can occur in connection with a query, an opinion survey, a desire on your part to contact us, an order placed by you, etc.   
We also require your personal data when you wish to make use of particular services (insofar as such services may be offered) on the Evonik Industries AG website such as the newsletter or forums. Should you decide to avail yourself of such a service, you will find for each service extensive information and pointers about the type, scope and utilization of the data that is required in order to use the service in question. 

### Protecting the privacy of children who use the internet 

Personal data pertaining to children are not knowingly gathered or used in any way. We are not generally aware of the age of the user of our websites. We have, however, taken no specific steps to give special protection to such data.   
As protecting children who use the internet is a matter of great importance to Evonik Industries AG. Evonik Industries AG therefore advises all parents and persons acting in loco parentis to show children how to deal responsibly and safely with personal data on the internet.   
Children should not send any personal data to Evonik Industries AG without the express permission of parents or a person acting in loco parentis. 

### How we use your data 

Evonik Industries AG collects, processes and utilizes all personal data stemming from your visit to the Evonik Industries AG website strictly in accordance with the applicable legal regulations.   
We use this personal data only for the purposes specified in the present declaration (e.g., to process a query or in connection with the utilization of internet services). In addition, we will only gather, process or use personal data if we need to do so in order to protect the legitimate business interests of Evonik Industries AG.   
Evonik Industries AG will not provide third parties with any personal data that you may have sent without first obtaining your express written permission. 

You can withdraw the consent you gave to use your personal data at any time with future effect by sending an email to the email address provided in the Legal Notice or to the data protection officer.   
We retain control over and take responsibility for the use of the personal data that you send to us. It is possible that some or all of this data is stored or processed in other countries (for example in the United States) that have different data protection laws from your country of residence. In this case, we will ensure that the company commissioned to process the data has taken appropriate steps to protect your personal data in accordance with the requirements applicable in your country of residence. 

### Information, changes and deletions with respect to your data 

Pursuant to the applicable legal regulations, you are entitled to query us in writing at any time as to which (if any) of your personal data we are currently archiving. We will then send you a letter containing the information requested. Please address your inquiry to the data protection officer. You may also arrange with him to have changes made in your data or to have such data deleted. 

### Storing your data 

The personal data of the data subject will be deleted or blocked as soon as the purpose of storage no longer applies. Furthermore, storage may occur if required by European or national laws in EU directives, laws or other regulations to which the controller is subject. Data will also be blocked or deleted if the storage period specified in one of the above-referenced standards expires unless there is a need for further storage of data for concluding a contract or for contract performance. 

### Protecting your data

Any data provided by you to Evonik Industries AG will be protected by suitable technical and organizational mechanisms against adventitious or intentional manipulation, loss or destruction, access by unauthorized persons, and against unauthorized disclosure to third parties. With this goal in mind, our security measures are continually monitored and enhanced in accordance with technological advances and organizational resources. 

### Use of social plugins 

Our website does not use any plugins for social networks. When integrating the icons of social networks such as Facebook, Twitter, XING, and LinkedIn, we only make reference to these networks with an external link. In some cases, the link takes you to a share function of the network in question. This means that you can share our website, which you called up, with other users directly using the page of the social network to which the sharing button belongs. 

### Contact form 

On our website is a contact form available which can be used for electronic contact. If a user accepted this option the data entered in the input mask will be transmitted to us and saved. In this context it does not pass on the data to third parties. The data is used exclusively for processing the conversation. Legal basis for the processing of the data is (in the presence of the consent of the user) Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a GDPR. 

### Your rights 

If Evonik processes personal data, you are a data subject in the definition of the GDPR and have the following data subject rights in accordance with Art 12 ff, GDPR: Right to information, right to correction, right to restriction of processing, right to deletion, right to information, right to data portability, right of objection, and right to file a complaint with a supervisory authority. 

### The Evonik Industries AG data protection officer 

Should you have any questions regarding the processing of your personal data, please do not hesitate to contact our data protection officer who, along with his team, will be more than happy to help you if you need any further information or have any complaints or problems in connection with the security of your data.

Evonik Industries AG  
Data protection  
Rellinghauser Straße 1—11   
45128 Essen   
Germany  
+49 201 177-2151  

Please note that this data protection declaration is subject to change in order to meet current requirements.

© Evonik Industries AG, latest update: May 25, 2018
